Finding Aid for the Susan Sontag Papers LSC.0612
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 6: Works by Susan Sontag, 1945-2004
  - Sub-series 6.2, 1960-2004; 113 boxes (56.50 lin. ft.) and 12 oversize boxes
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1984-1991, no date. (Box 61, Folder 13)
      Jonathan Cape. 6 pages.
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1978-1994, 2003-2004. (Box 61, Folder 14)
      Penguin. 31 pages.
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., ca. 1993-2003. (Box 61, Folder 15)
      UK: Vintage (Frances Coady, Caroline Michel, and Jorg Hensgen). 52 pages.
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1967-1984. (Box 61, Folder 16)
      UK miscellaneous. 6 pages.
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1980-1988. (Box 61, Folder 17)
      Brombergs. 32 pages.
    - Foreign Publishers and Farrar, Straus & Giroux., 1992-1993. (Box 61, Folder 18)
      Modern Library. 38 pages and 3 items.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996. (Box 65, Folder 1)
      Italian cinema. 13 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996. (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Italian translation. 7 pages and 1 item.
    - Century of Cinema., 1995-1996. (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Frankfurter Rundschau. 30 pages. Includes correspondence with Wolfram Schutte
    - Century of Cinema., no date. (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Typescript drafts. 57 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996. (Box 65, Folder 5)
      France: Nouvelle Revue Francaise. 25 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996. (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Corriere della Sera. 8 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996-2001. (Box 65, Folder 7)
      Parnassus. 13 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1997. (Box 65, Folder 8)
      The Best American Movie Writing. 7 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996-1997. (Box 65, Folder 9)
      Miscellaneous. 7 pages and 1 item.
    - Century of Cinema., 1987. (Box 65, Folder 10)
      Italian translation. 10 pages.
    - Dancer and the Dance., no date. (Box 65, Folder 11)
      Photocopied typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Dancer and the Dance., 1987. (Box 65, Folder 12)
      London Review of Books (correspondence, page proofs and draft with holograph corrections). 16 pages.
    - Dancer and the Dance., 1987. (Box 65, Folder 13)
      Vanity Fair (includes page proofs with holograph corrections). 12 pages.
    - Dancer and the Dance., no date. (Box 65, Folder 14)
      Typescript draft labelled "last version" with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Don Quixote., 1986 January 5. (Box 65, Folder 15)
      "When Writers Talk Among Themselves" article. 3 pages.
    - Don Quixote., no date. (Box 65, Folder 16)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 10 pages.
    - Idea of Europe (One More Elegy), (The)., 1988. (Box 65, Folder 17)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 34 pages.
    - Idea of Europe (One More Elegy), (The)., 1989. (Box 65, Folder 18)
      French translation. 17 pages.
    - On Ferdydurke., 1999-2000. (Box 65, Folder 19)
      Yale University Press (notes, page proofs with holograph corrections, etc.). 75 pages.
    - On Ferdydurke., 2000. (Box 65, Folder 20)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 53 pages.
    - In Memory of Their Feelings., ca. 1989. (Box 65, Folder 21)
      For Dancers on a Plane. Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 75 pages.
    - In Memory of Their Feelings., 1990. (Box 65, Folder 22)
      German translation. ca. 90 pages.
    - Danilo Kis., 1994-1995. (Box 65, Folder 23)
      Polish retranslation. 17 pages.
    - Danilo Kis., 1995. (Box 65, Folder 24)
      Spain: Letra Internacional. 11 pages.
    - Danilo Kis., 1995. (Box 65, Folder 25)
      Partisan Review. ca. 55 pages.
    - Danilo Kis., 1995. (Box 65, Folder 26)
      Parnasso. 2 pages.
    - Danilo Kis., 1990-1991. (Box 65, Folder 27)
      French translation. 5 pages.
    - Don Quixote., 1985-1990. (Box 65, Folder 28)
      Correspondence and photocopies of typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 7 pages.
    - Letter to Borges (A)., 1996. (Box 66, Folder 1)
      10 pages and 1 item.
    - For Available Light: A Brief Lexicon., no date. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      Final typescript draft with holograph corrections. 29 pages.
    - For Available Light: A Brief Lexicon., no date. (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Abridged version called "Lucinda Childs: Some notes on Choreography". 6 pages.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., no date. (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 17 pages.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., 1991. (Box 66, Folder 5)
      Italian translation. 21 pages.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., 1991 June 29. (Box 66, Folder 6)
      German translation. 1 item.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., 1990. (Box 66, Folder 7)
      La Nacion. ca. 50 pages and 2 items.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., 1990-1991. (Box 66, Folder 8)
      Notes, correspondence, and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 150 pages.
    - Machado de Assis Foreword., 1990. (Box 66, Folder 9)
      Epitaph of a Small Winner. Photocopy of Farrar, Straus & Giroux page proofs with holograph corrections.
    - Barthes Reader (A)., 1982. (Box 66, Folder 10)
      Bound uncorrected proof with dust jacket. 1 item.
    - Barthes Reader (A)., no date. (Box 66, Folder 11)
      Bound uncorrected proof with holograph corrections. 1 item.
    - Danilo Kis., 1991-1995. (Box 66, Folder 12)
      Homo Poeticus introducation. ca. 60 pages.
    - Lincoln Kirstein., no date. (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Revisions of single paragraph. 2 pages.
    - Lincoln Kirstein., no date. (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 13 pages.
    - Lincoln Kirstein., 1987 February 11. (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Computer printed galleys with holograph corrections. 1 item.
    - Lincoln Kirstein., 1987 May. (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Vanity Fair article. 2 pages.
    - Response to Questions about Intellectuals., 1997-1998. (Box 67, Folder 5)
      32 pages.
    - Poet's Prose (A)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 6)
      Photocopies of page proofs with holograph corrections. 7 pages. Written as introduction to Marina Tsvetayeva: a Captive Spirit.
    - Mind in Mourning (A)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Review of W.G. Sebald's Vertigo: typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 39 pages.
    - Novel into Film: Fassbinder's Berlin Alexanderplatz., no date. (Box 67, Folder 8)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. Pages 2-16.
    - Novel into Film: Fassbinder's Berlin Alexanderplatz., no date. (Box 67, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of later typescript draft with holograph corrections. 113 pages.
    - Novel into Film: Fassbinder's Berlin Alexanderplatz., no date. (Box 67, Folder 10)
      Various typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 15 pages.
    - Novel into Film: Fassbinder's Berlin Alexanderplatz., 1999-2000. (Box 67, Folder 11)
      Notes and correspondence. 42 pages.
    - Poet's Prose (A)., 1983. (Box 67, Folder 12)
      Galley and typescript draft with holograph corrections. 11 pages and 1 item. Written as introduction to Marina Tsvetayeva: a Captive Spirit.
    - Certain Mapplethorpes., 1985. (Box 67, Folder 13)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 26 pages.
    - Ecstacy of Lament (An)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 14)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Ecstacy of Lament (An)., 1997-1998. (Box 67, Folder 15)
      Threepenny Review. 22 pages.
    - Pedro Paramo Introduction., 1992. (Box 67, Folder 16)
      Juan Rulfo re-translation. Correspondence, notes, and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 50 pages.
    - Place for Fantasy (A)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 17)
      Grottos: Caves of Mystery and Magic. Photocopy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Pelleas et Melisande., 1996-1997. (Box 67, Folder 18)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 70 pages.
    - Pelleas et Melisande., 1999. (Box 67, Folder 19)
      German translation. 6 pages and 1 item.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 20)
      Notes and typescript draft with holograph corrections. 3 pages. Mauritshuis
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., 1989. (Box 67, Folder 21)
      Correspondence. 2 pages.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., 1987. (Box 67, Folder 22)
      Correspondence with Fritz Raddatz. 18 pages.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., 1987. (Box 67, Folder 23)
      Photocopy of page proofs with holograph corrections. 10 pages.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., no date. (Box 67, Folder 24)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 54 pages.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., 1986-1989. (Box 67, Folder 25)
      Lurens van Krevelen. 18 pages.
    - Pleasure of the Image (The)., 1987 September 20. (Box 67, Folder 26)
      Letter from Daniel Halpern. 1 page.
    - Questions of Travel., ca. 1984. (Box 67, Folder 27)
      Photocopy of pages proofs from Times Literary Supplement with holograph corrections. 4 pages. Published as Model Destinations. See Communism and the Intellectuals
    - Questions of Travel., ca. 1980-1985. (Box 67, Folder 28)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. 15 pages. Published as Model Destinations. See Communism and the Intellectuals
    - Being Translated., 1995-1997. (Box 67, Folder 29)
      Correspondence. 24 pages.
    - Being Translated., 1995. (Box 68, Folder 1)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 125 pages.
    - There and Here., 1995. (Box 68, Folder 2)
      The Nation. 23 pages and 2 items.
    - There and Here., 1995 December 25. (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Original. 3 pages.
    - There and Here., 1995. (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Copies including typescript drafts. 36 pages.
    - There and Here., 1996. (Box 68, Folder 5)
      Japan. 7 pages.
    - There and Here., 1995. (Box 68, Folder 6)
      Spanish. ca. 80 pages and 1 item.
    - There and Here., 1995-1996. (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Germany: Lettre International. ca. 50 pages.
    - There and Here., 1996. (Box 68, Folder 8)
      Australian. 10 pages.
    - There and Here., no date. (Box 68, Folder 9)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 60 pages.
    - There and Here., 1996. (Box 68, Folder 10)
      Miscellaneous. 2 pages and 1 item.
    - Thirty Years Later., no date. (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 27 pages.
    - Thirty Years Later., 1996. (Box 68, Folder 12)
      Threepenny Review. 13 pages.
    - Thirty Years Later., 1995-1996. (Box 68, Folder 13)
      Spanish translation. ca. 80 pages.
    - Thirty Years Later., 1997. (Box 68, Folder 14)
      Italian translation. 23 pages.
    - Thirty Years Later., no date. (Box 68, Folder 15)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 42 pages.
    - Thirty Years Later., 1996 May 11. (Box 68, Folder 16)
      Spanish newspapers. 2 items.
    - Wagner's Fluids., 1988. (Box 68, Folder 17)
      Swedish translation. 3 pages.
    - Wagner's Fluids., 1988 January 24. (Box 68, Folder 18)
      Spanish translation. 1 item.
    - Wagner's Fluids., 1993. (Box 68, Folder 19)
      German translation. 2 items.
    - Brother Carl., 1970-1972. (Box 69, Folder 1)
      Early typescript synopsis and script with holograph corrections (under tentative title: Testament). 80 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970-1972. (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Correspondence, lists, and miscellaneous ephemera. 20 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1999. (Box 69, Folder 3)
      YWCA. 12 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 69, Folder 4)
      Photographs on set. 17 items. Includes one of Sontag
    - Brother Carl., no date. (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Dual column scripts. ca. 144 pages. Includes small photographs
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 69, Folder 6)
      Duplicate of production book (not used for shooting). Folder 1 of 2. ca. 100 pages. Includes miscellaneous ephemera.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 69, Folder 7)
      Duplicate of production book (not used for shooting). Folder 2 of 2. ca. 100 pages. Includes miscellaneous ephemera and small photographs (includes 2 of Sontag)
    - Promised Lands., no date. (Box 69, Folder 8)
      Synopsis. 4 pages.
    - Promised Lands., 1973-1974. (Box 69, Folder 9)
      Notes, spiral notebook, and ephemera. 19 pages and 3 items.
    - Promised Lands., no date. (Box 69, Folder 10)
      Interviews list. 2 pages.
    - Promised Lands., 1986-1988. (Box 69, Folder 11)
      France. 12 pages and 4 items.
    - Promised Lands., no date. (Box 69, Folder 12)
      Film stills. 20 items.
    - Promised Lands., 1974-1997. (Box 69, Folder 13)
      Photocopies of articles and reviews. ca. 80 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 70, Folder 1)
      Spiralbound final draft of film script. 1 item.
    - Brother Carl., no date. (Box 70, Folder 2)
      Red spiralbound notebook with notes. 1 item.
    - Brother Carl., no date. (Box 70, Folder 3)
      First typescript draft of actor's script with holograph corrections. 162 pages.
    - Brother Carl., no date. (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Later typescript draft of actor's script with holograph corrections. 68 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 70, Folder 5)
      Carbon copy of late typescript draft of actor's script with holograph corrections. 83 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 70, Folder 6)
      Carbon copy of intermediate typescript draft of actor's script with holograph corrections. 70 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1972. (Box 70, Folder 7)
      Typescript drafts of forward with holograph corrections for Farrar, Straus & Giroux edition. 22 pages.
    - Brother Carl., ca. 1970. (Box 70, Folder 8)
      Stills from film. 21 items. Includes stills of Sontag
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 70, Folder 9)
      Production book with stills from various scenes. Folder 1 of 2. ca. 80 pages.
    - Brother Carl., 1970. (Box 70, Folder 10)
      Production book with stills from various scenes. Folder 2 of 2. ca. 80 pages.
    - Hodgkin., 1994-1996. (Box 71, Folder 1)
      Essay correspondence. ca. 100 pages.
    - Hodgkin., 1995. (Box 71, Folder 2)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 69 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., no date. (Box 71, Folder 3)
      Alinari. First typescript draft with holograph corrections. 10 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., no date. (Box 71, Folder 4)
      Photocopy of galleys with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., no date. (Box 71, Folder 5)
      Notes. 2 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., 1988. (Box 71, Folder 6)
      Threepenny Review. 5 items.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., no date. (Box 71, Folder 7)
      Intermediate typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., 1987. (Box 71, Folder 8)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 18 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., 1987. (Box 71, Folder 9)
      Photocopy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., 1987. (Box 71, Folder 10)
      Letters and telegrams. 7 pages.
    - Italy: 100 Years of Photography Introduction., 1987. (Box 71, Folder 11)
      Correspondence with editor. 8 pages.
    - Promised Lands., 1974-1986. (Box 71, Folder 12)
      Miscellaneous. 9 items.
    - Bunraku., no date. (Box 71, Folder 12)
      Photocopies of pages proofs from Japan Society with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Bunraku., 1984. (Box 71, Folder 13)
      Threepenny Review. 1 item.
    - Bellocq., 1995-1996. (Box 71, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Mark Holborn and Jonathan Cape. ca. 70 pages.
    - Bellocq., 1995. (Box 71, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with Sharon Delano. 10 pages.
    - Bellocq., no date. (Box 71, Folder 16)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 21 pages.
    - Century of Cinema., 1996-1997. (Box 71, Folder 17)
      New York Times. ca. 50 pages.
    - Writing Itself: On Roland Barthes., 1982. (Box 71, Folder 18)
      Various notes. 34 pages.
    - Writing Itself: On Roland Barthes., 1982. (Box 71, Folder 19)
      Page proofs and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 250 pages.
    - When Writers Talk Among Themselves., 1985 December 23. (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Typescript drafts (and carbon copies) with holograph corrections. 30 pages.
    - When Writers Talk Among Themselves., ca. 1985. (Box 74, Folder 2)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 26 pages and 1 envelope. Notes on envelope. All folder contents originally with Sartre Abdication materials, Box 273 Folder 5, 7)
    - When Writers Talk Among Themselves., no date. (Box 74, Folder 3)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 44 pages.
    - When Writers Talk Among Themselves., 1986. (Box 74, Folder 4)
      German translation. 3 items.
    - View from the Ark (The)., no date. (Box 74, Folder 5)
      For Richard Misrach's Violent Legacies. Typescript intermediate draft with holograph corrections. 7 pages. Also titles Noah's Ark
    - View from the Ark (The)., no date. (Box 74, Folder 6)
      Photocopy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 7 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., ca. 1992. (Box 74, Folder 7)
      Photocopy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 12 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., no date. (Box 74, Folder 8)
      Typescript final draft. 12 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., ca. 1992. (Box 74, Folder 9)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 70 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1991-1992. (Box 74, Folder 10)
      Letters. 2 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1992 June 29. (Box 74, Folder 11)
      Page proofs. 6 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1992. (Box 74, Folder 12)
      Final page proofs. 14 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1991-1992. (Box 74, Folder 13)
      Letters from Richard Misrach. 5 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1992. (Box 74, Folder 14)
      Correspondence between Karla Eoff and Melissa Harris. 4 pages.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1995. (Box 74, Folder 15)
      Correspondence with SZ Magazine. 3 items.
    - View from the Ark (The)., 1992. (Box 74, Folder 16)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 136 pages.
    - Idea of a Narrative in New Fiction and New Cinema (The)., no date. (Box 74, Folder 17)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 30 pages.
    - William Burroughs and the Novel., no date. (Box 74, Folder 18)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 60 pages.
    - Exile's Cosmopolis (The)., 1984. (Box 74, Folder 19)
      Introduction for Edgardo Cozarinsky's Urban Voodoo: correspondence and typescript draft with holograph corrections. 12 pages.
    - New Life for an Old One (A)., 1964. (Box 74, Folder 20)
      Review of John Hawkes' Second Skin: typescript draft with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Response to WIN Magazine., 1968 March 30. (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Viva Che., 1968. (Box 74, Folder 22)
      Carbon copy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 6 pages.
    - Godard., 1967. (Box 74, Folder 23)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 20 pages.
    - Laughter in the Dark., no date. (Box 74, Folder 24)
      Review of James Purdy's Cabot Wright Begins: typescript draft with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Virginia is a State of Mind., 1963. (Box 74, Folder 25)
      Review of Yves Berger's The Garden: typescript draft with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Review of John Rublowsky's Pop Art., 1965. (Box 74, Folder 26)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. 4 pages.
    - Year's Work in Literature (The)., 1966. (Box 74, Folder 27)
      Carbon copy of typescript final draft with holograph corrections. 86 pages.
    - Year's Work in Literature (The)., no date. (Box 74, Folder 28)
      Early typescript draft of incomplete essay with holograph corrections. 65 pages.
    - Year's Work in Literature (The)., 1965, no date. (Box 74, Folder 29)
      Notes, bibliography, and contract. 18 pages.
    - Voluptuary's Catechism (A)., 1963. (Box 75, Folder 1)
      Review of Jean Genet's Our Lady of the Flowers: carbon copy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 6 pages.
    - Man with a Pain., 1960-1963. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Cuban Revolution., no date. (Box 75, Folder 3)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections and telegram. Pages 1-20 and 1 page.
    - Review of John Osborne's Inadmissable Evidence., no date. (Box 75, Folder 4)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. 3 pages.
    - On Sartre and the Nobel Prize., 1964. (Box 75, Folder 5)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections and newspaper clippings. 3 items.
    - Barthes., 1968. (Box 75, Folder 6)
      Preface to Roland Barthes' Writing Degree Zero: typescript drafts with holograph corrections and page proofs. 34 pages.
    - Review of Maurice Nadeau's The History of Surrealism., 1965 October 25. (Box 75, Folder 7)
      Carbon copy of typescript draft with holograph corrections. 8 pages.
    - Avante Garde and Contemporary Literature (The)., no date. (Box 75, Folder 8)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. ca. 90 pages.
    - Art of Telling (The): Laura Riding., no date. (Box 75, Folder 9)
      Notes and typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 30 pages.
    - Contemporary European Literature., no date. (Box 75, Folder 10)
      Notes and typescript draft with holograph corrections. 9 pages.
    - Psychoanalytic Dialogue (A)., 1965-1966. (Box 75, Folder 11)
      Review of The Letters of Sigmund Freud and Karl Abraham: typescript drafts with holograph corrections and reviews in Book Week. 5 items.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., 1969. (Box 75, Folder 12)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections. 37 pages.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., 1969 July. (Box 75, Folder 13)
      Ramparts Magazine. 2 items.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., no date. (Box 75, Folder 14)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. Pages 22-27.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., 1968-1969. (Box 75, Folder 15)
      Preparatory notes and newspaper clippings. 9 pages and 3 items.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., 1969. (Box 75, Folder 16)
      Rampart's setting copy. 1 item.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., no date. (Box 75, Folder 17)
      Early typescript draft with holograph corrections. Pages 22-28.
    - Letter from Sweden (A)., 1969. (Box 75, Folder 18)
      Typescript draft with holograph corrections. 25 pages.
    - Against Interpretation., 1962. (Box 75, Folder 19)
      Piety Without Content, review of Religion from Tolstoy to Camus. Magazine article and typescript draft with holograph corrections. 10 pages.
    - On Novels and Films., no date. (Box 75, Folder 20)
      Typescript drafts with holograph corrections; holograph notes; interview drafts. 22 pages.
    - Notes on Optimism., no date. (Box 75, Folder 21)
      Typescript draft titled Optimism of the Will with holograph corrections. 8 pages.
    - Notes on Optimism., no date. (Box 75, Folder 22)
      Early typescript draft titled Optimism of the Will with holograph corrections. 7 pages.
    - Notes on Optimism., no date. (Box 75, Folder 23)
      Typescript draft titled Hints & Homilies for Aspiring Optimists with holograph corrections. 7 pages.
    - Notes on Optimism., no date. (Box 75, Folder 24)
      Typescript drafts titled In the Last Days of the Republic with holograph corrections. 13 pages.
    - Notes on Optimism., no date. (Box 75, Folder 25)
      Typescript drafts in conjunction with David Rieff. 6 pages.